Sanjida Afreen

sanjidaaf@outlook.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/sanjidaa/ | https://sanjidaa.carrd.co/ | Toronto, ON

PROFILE OVERVIEW

Highly skilled Data Analyst with over 2 years of experience in developing advanced Power BI dashboards, application configuration, and data integration. Proven ability to troubleshoot application and integration issues, manage master data for new business needs.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Honors Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Apr 2024

York University (Lassonde School of Engineering)

Toronto, ON

Relevant Courses: Database Management System, Big Data Systems, Computer Network Protocols and Applications

Certificates: Google Cybersecurity Professional, **Google** Data Analytics, **Microsoft** Cybersecurity Analyst Professional, Developing Serverless Solutions on **AWS**, NoSQL and DBaaS 101, **DevOps** on AWS, Scrum Master

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst - Program Assistant | York University

Toronto, ON | Mar 2024 - Present

- Designed and implemented 5 advanced **Power BI** dashboards, enhancing feedback analysis efficiency by 40%, tracking student employment trends over 5 years to highlight a 700% program growth, and boosting job posting visibility by 25%.
- Conducted **Microsoft Forms** to collect detailed insights on student and employer satisfaction, utilizing **Microsoft Excel Power Query** for data transformation and **DAX** for sophisticated data modeling and analysis.
- Created and maintained **SharePoint sites** and lists as data sources for Power BI dashboards, enabling nightly refresh and automation to ensure up-to-date and accurate reporting.

Data Analyst Intern | TC Energy

Calgary, AB | May 2022 – Apr 2023

- Built 6 **Power BI** dashboards handling over **3M** rows per dataset in collaboration with the Product Delivery team and integrated data from **Amazon Redshift** for enhanced performance.
- Mastered DAX, SQL, and Power Query to boost data analysis and visualization efficiency.
- Resolved over 80 IT service requests via **ServiceNow**, improving response times and user satisfaction, with proficiency in QA testing and validation environments.
- Developed Canvas and Model-Driven **Power Apps** for streamlining licensing processes for **Liquid Pipelines** business, improving their efficiency by 40% through **PowerAutomate** workflow solutions.
- Ensured high data security in Power Platform development, aligning with industry compliance standards.
- Integrated multiple data sources, including **Dataverse** and **SharePoint** to deliver enhanced and comprehensive data-driven user experiences.

Cloud Developer Intern | *TC Energy*

Calgary, AB | Jan 2022 - May 2022

- Developed web applications using **AWS Amplify, React, Lambda (Python)**, and **API Gateway**, following **Agile** methodologies and **Azure DevOps** for secure project management and documentation.
- Improved code quality and reduced post-production issues by 20% through **Pytest** framework.

ACTIVITIES AND LEADERSHIP

Hackathon Member Feb 2021

Lassonde Games

Toronto, ON

- Developed a software system to improve the autonomy and accessibility of healthcare among the senior citizens in Toronto using **JavaScript** and **HTML**.
- Constructed a prototype schematic of our team's aquatic cleanup system using **TinkerCAD** that passively floats on the water body and catches any garbage discarded into it.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Sales Management Dashboard Project https://github.com/Sanjida-a/SalesAnalysis

June 2024

- Developed an executive sales report for sales managers using Power BI, featuring daily updates and filters for real-time insights.
- Extracted and transformed data using SQL, SQL Server Management Studio, and Microsoft Excel.
- Designed a comprehensive data model in **Power BI** using **DAX**, connecting sales and budget data for detailed analysis.
- Visualized business proposal, user stories and profiles using Canva for clarity and stakeholder alignment.

SKILLS

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C, Python, SQL, DAX
- Developer Tools: Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, Git, MySQL, JUnit, Node, Power Query
- Security Frameworks and Compliance: NIST, INFOSEC, Regulatory Compliance
- Project Management: Leading smaller projects or initiatives, RPA and Power BI development.
- Technical Writing: Proficient in technical writing and documentation, experience with Visio.